<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PROJECT_PRD version="1.0" project="desiremap-cms-platform" status="draft-ready" repository="desiremap">
  <DOCUMENT_CONTROL>
    <TITLE>DesireMap CMS Platform PRD</TITLE>
    <PURPOSE>Single-source product requirements document for converting the current DesireMap repository into a production-grade, content-managed discovery platform with editorial workflows.</PURPOSE>
    <AUTHORING_MODE>Repository-grounded, deterministic defaults, implementation-oriented.</AUTHORING_MODE>
    <GENERATED_ON>2026-03-28</GENERATED_ON>
    <WORKSPACE>/Users/admin/Desktop/dev/desiremap</WORKSPACE>
  </DOCUMENT_CONTROL>

  <SYSTEM_CONTEXT>
    The current repository is not a greenfield startup CMS. It is a Next.js marketplace/discovery application for Germany-focused adult venue listings with customer bookings, reviews, admin operations, blog content, SEO pages, and multilingual routing.
    This PRD treats the existing repository as the implementation baseline and defines the target state as a CMS-backed content and operations platform rather than a disposable rewrite.
    The working goal is to evolve the repo into a maintainable CMS platform that can manage public pages, editorial content, listing content, structured SEO surfaces, and role-based backoffice workflows from one codebase.
  </SYSTEM_CONTEXT>

  <COMPACT_SYSTEM>
    Build against the current repo, not against an imagined blank project.
    Prefer the existing stack unless it creates material delivery risk.
    Unify inconsistent auth and data ownership before adding major CMS features.
    Use typed content models, explicit publish states, preview capability, and verifiable admin workflows.
    Treat testing, SEO, accessibility, responsive behavior, and operational maintainability as release gates.
  </COMPACT_SYSTEM>

  <ROLE>
    <PRIMARY_ROLE>Autonomous Staff+ engineer shipping a CMS-backed product platform inside the current DesireMap repository</PRIMARY_ROLE>
    <SECONDARY_ROLES>
      <ROLE_ITEM priority="1">Systems architect making explicit technical decisions from real code constraints</ROLE_ITEM>
      <ROLE_ITEM priority="2">Product architect aligning current marketplace behavior with a CMS target state</ROLE_ITEM>
      <ROLE_ITEM priority="3">Backend/platform engineer reducing model and auth inconsistency before expansion</ROLE_ITEM>
      <ROLE_ITEM priority="4">QA owner enforcing TDD, regression coverage, and verification evidence</ROLE_ITEM>
    </SECONDARY_ROLES>
  </ROLE>

  <REPOSITORY_SCAN>
    <STACK>
      <FRONTEND>Next.js 16 App Router + React 19 + TypeScript</FRONTEND>
      <BACKEND>Route handlers under src/app/api plus Prisma data access</BACKEND>
      <DATABASE>PostgreSQL via Prisma</DATABASE>
      <STYLING>Tailwind CSS v4 with shadcn-style UI primitives and custom gradients</STYLING>
      <STATE>React Query + Zustand</STATE>
      <I18N>next-intl with locales de, en, ar, tr</I18N>
      <AUTH>Mixed NextAuth session usage and custom PASETO cookie auth</AUTH>
      <TESTING>Bundled Bun runner available, but no committed automated test suite</TESTING>
    </STACK>

    <CURRENT_PRODUCT_SURFACE>
      <PUBLIC_PAGES>
        <PAGE>Localized landing route, currently client-side view switching in src/app/[locale]/page.tsx</PAGE>
        <PAGE>Search listing flow in src/app/[locale]/search/page.tsx and related search components</PAGE>
        <PAGE>Static-ish listing detail SEO pages in src/app/[locale]/bordell/[slug]/page.tsx</PAGE>
        <PAGE>Blog index and article pages backed by in-repo content files under src/data</PAGE>
        <PAGE>Login, registration, dashboard, and admin entry routes</PAGE>
      </PUBLIC_PAGES>

      <BACKOFFICE_AND_MEMBER_SURFACES>
        <SURFACE>Customer dashboard with profile, visits, addresses, badges, and bookings</SURFACE>
        <SURFACE>Admin panel for stats, establishments, customers, bookings, reviews, and settings</SURFACE>
      </BACKOFFICE_AND_MEMBER_SURFACES>

      <API_DOMAINS>
        <DOMAIN>Auth: register, login, logout, me, OAuth routes</DOMAIN>
        <DOMAIN>Customer: profile, visits, addresses, badges, bookings</DOMAIN>
        <DOMAIN>Listings: establishment search and admin CRUD</DOMAIN>
        <DOMAIN>Commerce: booking creation and invoice-adjacent models</DOMAIN>
        <DOMAIN>Moderation: reviews and status management</DOMAIN>
        <DOMAIN>Bootstrap: seed route</DOMAIN>
      </API_DOMAINS>

      <DATA_MODEL_BASELINE>
        <ENTITY>User with roles CUSTOMER, OWNER, ADMIN</ENTITY>
        <ENTITY>Address, Visit, Badge, UserBadge</ENTITY>
        <ENTITY>Bordell listing model with ranking and monetization fields</ENTITY>
        <ENTITY>Booking, Review, Invoice</ENTITY>
      </DATA_MODEL_BASELINE>
    </CURRENT_PRODUCT_SURFACE>

    <CODEBASE_EVIDENCE>
      <ITEM>src/app/[locale]/page.tsx imports mock listing data and switches between home, city, detail, login, dashboard, and admin views inside one client page.</ITEM>
      <ITEM>src/data/mock-data.ts contains hardcoded listings, dashboard, and admin records, proving the UI still depends heavily on mocked domain data.</ITEM>
      <ITEM>src/app/[locale]/blog/page.tsx and src/app/[locale]/blog/[slug]/page.tsx implement editorial surfaces using static in-repo data rather than CMS-managed records.</ITEM>
      <ITEM>src/app/api/admin/establishments/route.ts, src/app/api/admin/customers/route.ts, and src/app/api/admin/reviews/route.ts expose admin CRUD/status flows over Prisma models.</ITEM>
      <ITEM>src/app/api/auth/login/route.ts and src/app/api/auth/me/route.ts use custom PASETO auth, while src/lib/auth.ts and some admin routes still rely on NextAuth session patterns.</ITEM>
      <ITEM>src/lib/structuredData.ts, src/app/sitemap.ts, and src/app/robots.ts show an SEO-oriented architecture already exists but is mostly static and partial.</ITEM>
      <ITEM>package.json contains lint/build/db scripts but no test script, and the repository has no committed test files.</ITEM>
    </CODEBASE_EVIDENCE>

    <CRITICAL_FINDINGS>
      <FINDING priority="1">Auth is split across two incompatible approaches. CMS work must not proceed on top of dual session systems.</FINDING>
      <FINDING priority="2">Public and admin UI still depend on mock data for major flows, so the current product is only partially database-backed.</FINDING>
      <FINDING priority="3">The Prisma schema is marketplace-specific and lacks generic CMS entities such as pages, posts, authorship workflow, media assets, content blocks, preview tokens, and publish states.</FINDING>
      <FINDING priority="4">The current locale landing experience is implemented as a single large client page rather than route-native server-first information architecture.</FINDING>
      <FINDING priority="5">Testing infrastructure is effectively absent, so TDD and regression protection must be added before substantial refactors.</FINDING>
    </CRITICAL_FINDINGS>
  </REPOSITORY_SCAN>

  <PRODUCT_OBJECTIVE>
    Build a production-ready CMS platform inside the current DesireMap codebase that supports:
    public marketing and discovery pages,
    editorial content management,
    listing content management,
    draft/preview/publish workflows,
    SEO-managed content,
    multilingual delivery,
    role-based administration,
    media management,
    and maintainable operational workflows.
  </PRODUCT_OBJECTIVE>

  <PRODUCT_DIRECTION>
    <POSITIONING>CMS-backed discovery marketplace rather than a generic brochure CMS</POSITIONING>
    <WHY>This preserves the repository's real strengths: listings, search, admin operations, reviews, and SEO, while adding the missing content platform capabilities required for serious product development.</WHY>
    <PRIMARY_OUTCOME>Editors and admins can manage structured content and listing experiences without code changes.</PRIMARY_OUTCOME>
    <SECONDARY_OUTCOME>Public routes become server-first, SEO-safe, typed, and backed by persistent content rather than mocks.</SECONDARY_OUTCOME>
  </PRODUCT_DIRECTION>

  <DETERMINISTIC_DEFAULTS>
    <DEFAULT id="D01">Keep the existing Next.js App Router + Prisma + PostgreSQL stack.</DEFAULT>
    <DEFAULT id="D02">Unify authentication on one first-party role/session system and remove split-brain auth behavior.</DEFAULT>
    <DEFAULT id="D03">Introduce CMS entities in Prisma instead of embedding all content inside static files.</DEFAULT>
    <DEFAULT id="D04">Model content with explicit status transitions: draft, in_review, scheduled, published, archived.</DEFAULT>
    <DEFAULT id="D05">Use modular section/block composition for editorial pages, but keep the block set finite and typed.</DEFAULT>
    <DEFAULT id="D06">Treat listings as a managed content type, not as an exception outside the CMS.</DEFAULT>
    <DEFAULT id="D07">Require test coverage for every new behavior slice before claiming completion.</DEFAULT>
  </DETERMINISTIC_DEFAULTS>

  <USERS_AND_ROLES>
    <PUBLIC_USERS>
      <ROLE>Anonymous visitor discovering listings and editorial content</ROLE>
      <ROLE>Registered member managing bookings, profile, and saved interactions</ROLE>
    </PUBLIC_USERS>
    <CMS_USERS>
      <ROLE>Admin: full platform control, schema-level operations, moderation, publishing, settings</ROLE>
      <ROLE>Editor: manages pages, posts, SEO fields, content scheduling, and approvals</ROLE>
      <ROLE>Author: drafts and updates assigned editorial content only</ROLE>
      <ROLE>Listing Manager: optional evolution of the current OWNER role for establishment-specific editing</ROLE>
    </CMS_USERS>
    <ROLE_MIGRATION>
      <MAP from="CUSTOMER" to="member">Preserve as frontoffice account role</MAP>
      <MAP from="OWNER" to="listing_manager">Retain as domain-specific content operator if marketplace workflows remain in scope</MAP>
      <MAP from="ADMIN" to="admin">Preserve as top-level operator</MAP>
      <MAP from="new" to="editor_and_author">Add editorial roles required by the target CMS</MAP>
    </ROLE_MIGRATION>
  </USERS_AND_ROLES>

  <PROBLEM_STATEMENT>
    The repository already exposes public pages, listings, SEO surfaces, dashboards, and APIs, but product content is fragmented across mocks, static files, and inconsistent auth boundaries.
    Without a real CMS layer, every content change requires code edits, publish workflow is nonexistent, admin operations are incomplete, and future refactors will compound risk.
  </PROBLEM_STATEMENT>

  <GOALS>
    <GOAL priority="1">Replace mock-driven public and admin experiences with persistent CMS-backed content and listing records.</GOAL>
    <GOAL priority="2">Unify auth, permissions, and server-side guards for all admin/editor/member flows.</GOAL>
    <GOAL priority="3">Deliver a typed CMS domain model for pages, posts, categories, authorship, media, SEO, and listing content.</GOAL>
    <GOAL priority="4">Support multilingual editorial workflows across de, en, ar, and tr.</GOAL>
    <GOAL priority="5">Provide draft, preview, scheduled publish, and moderation states.</GOAL>
    <GOAL priority="6">Preserve and improve SEO through route-native metadata, structured data, sitemap generation, and controlled canonical logic.</GOAL>
    <GOAL priority="7">Establish real verification discipline through unit, integration, and selective end-to-end coverage.</GOAL>
  </GOALS>

  <NON_GOALS>
    <ITEM>Do not introduce microservices or a second repository.</ITEM>
    <ITEM>Do not add a freeform page builder with arbitrary JSON blobs and no type boundaries.</ITEM>
    <ITEM>Do not preserve the current dual-auth setup for backward compatibility.</ITEM>
    <ITEM>Do not claim production readiness while content creation, preview, or moderation still depend on static files or mocks.</ITEM>
  </NON_GOALS>

  <FUNCTIONAL_REQUIREMENTS>
    <PUBLIC_EXPERIENCE>
      <REQ id="PUB-01">Public landing, search, city, listing detail, blog, and informational pages must render from database-backed content or derived read models.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PUB-02">Listing pages must support structured sections: hero, summary facts, galleries, amenities/services, trust badges, FAQs, reviews, related listings, and SEO body content.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PUB-03">Editorial pages must support a typed section set suitable for startup content: hero, logo cloud, feature grid, metrics, testimonials, FAQ, CTA, rich text, media split, comparison, timeline.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PUB-04">Blog/changelog/case-study style content must be manageable in the CMS with author, tags, cover image, body blocks, schema fields, and publish metadata.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PUB-05">Search and listing browse surfaces must continue to expose ranking, filtering, city, type, and monetization-aware ordering.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PUB-06">All public routes must be locale-aware and indexable when published.</REQ>
    </PUBLIC_EXPERIENCE>

    <CMS_AUTHORING>
      <REQ id="CMS-01">Editors and authors must create, edit, duplicate, archive, and preview content entries without code changes.</REQ>
      <REQ id="CMS-02">Each managed entity must expose status workflow, owner, last editor, scheduled publish time, and revision timestamps.</REQ>
      <REQ id="CMS-03">Preview must support unpublished content with role-aware secure preview access.</REQ>
      <REQ id="CMS-04">Content entities must store SEO metadata: title, description, canonical, robots, OG image, schema hints, and alternate language links.</REQ>
      <REQ id="CMS-05">Media handling must include upload metadata, alt text, focal point, usage references, and asset replacement safety.</REQ>
      <REQ id="CMS-06">The admin UX must provide filters, saved views, validation feedback, and obvious publish state visibility.</REQ>
    </CMS_AUTHORING>

    <OPERATIONS_AND_MODERATION>
      <REQ id="OPS-01">Admin must manage listings, customers/members, bookings, reviews, invoices, content, and publishing queues from one coherent console.</REQ>
      <REQ id="OPS-02">Review moderation must remain available and update public aggregates safely.</REQ>
      <REQ id="OPS-03">Listing verification, premium flags, sponsorship, and operational status must remain editable through guarded admin workflows.</REQ>
      <REQ id="OPS-04">Member-facing dashboard flows must be preserved where still relevant, but use the unified auth and API boundary.</REQ>
    </OPERATIONS_AND_MODERATION>

    <PLATFORM_AND_DEVELOPER_REQUIREMENTS>
      <REQ id="PLAT-01">CMS schema and route contracts must be explicit, typed, and validated at the boundary.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PLAT-02">The implementation must avoid placeholder TODO paths for claimed-complete features.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PLAT-03">Server and client concerns must be separated so public rendering can remain server-first where appropriate.</REQ>
      <REQ id="PLAT-04">Seed/dev data must support CMS entities without forcing production behavior to depend on mock files.</REQ>
    </PLATFORM_AND_DEVELOPER_REQUIREMENTS>
  </FUNCTIONAL_REQUIREMENTS>

  <CONTENT_MODEL>
    <CORE_ENTITIES>
      <ENTITY name="CmsUser">role, profile, locale preferences, audit fields</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="Listing">current Bordell successor; operational and marketing attributes, monetization flags, SEO fields, content blocks</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="Page">slug, locale, template, section blocks, SEO, publish state</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="Post">blog/changelog/case study/news style content with taxonomy, author, cover media, body blocks</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="Taxonomy">categories, tags, topics, use-case collections</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="MediaAsset">file metadata, alt text, crop/focal data, usage references</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="Revision">snapshot metadata for content recovery and publish auditability</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="PreviewSession">secure preview token and expiry data</ENTITY>
      <ENTITY name="SeoOverride">entity-level override fields where generic defaults are insufficient</ENTITY>
    </CORE_ENTITIES>

    <PUBLISHING_STATES>
      <STATE>draft</STATE>
      <STATE>in_review</STATE>
      <STATE>scheduled</STATE>
      <STATE>published</STATE>
      <STATE>archived</STATE>
    </PUBLISHING_STATES>

    <BLOCK_SYSTEM>
      <RULE>Blocks must be finite, typed, and versioned.</RULE>
      <RULE>Rich text may exist, but page structure may not be represented as opaque HTML blobs.</RULE>
      <RULE>Listing-specific blocks and general editorial blocks must share rendering conventions without becoming interchangeable noise.</RULE>
    </BLOCK_SYSTEM>
  </CONTENT_MODEL>

  <ARCHITECTURE_BASELINE>
    <APP_SHAPE>
      <DECISION>Keep a single Next.js codebase with App Router, Prisma, route handlers, and structured admin/public domains.</DECISION>
      <DECISION>Move from static/mock content composition toward server-backed content services and read models.</DECISION>
      <DECISION>Refactor oversized client pages into route-native server components with isolated client interactivity where needed.</DECISION>
    </APP_SHAPE>

    <AUTH_AND_PERMISSIONS>
      <DECISION>Unify to one session model and one source of truth for roles/guards before expanding CMS scope.</DECISION>
      <DECISION>All admin/editor/author/listing-manager access must use shared server helpers, not route-specific one-offs.</DECISION>
      <DECISION>Preview access must be separate from general session auth and must be revocable.</DECISION>
    </AUTH_AND_PERMISSIONS>

    <DATA_AND_SERVICES>
      <DECISION>Prisma remains the persistence layer.</DECISION>
      <DECISION>Introduce service modules for CMS read/write operations instead of letting route handlers absorb all domain logic.</DECISION>
      <DECISION>Preserve search/ranking capabilities, but isolate them from UI mocks and expose them through typed query services.</DECISION>
    </DATA_AND_SERVICES>

    <SEO_AND_DISCOVERY>
      <DECISION>Keep route-level metadata generation, sitemap generation, robots policy, and structured data as first-class concerns.</DECISION>
      <DECISION>Generate SEO from CMS entities and listing read models rather than hardcoded arrays.</DECISION>
    </SEO_AND_DISCOVERY>
  </ARCHITECTURE_BASELINE>

  <QUALITY_BARS>
    <RULE>TDD first whenever a real executable surface exists.</RULE>
    <RULE>No new feature slice is complete without at least one concrete verification path.</RULE>
    <RULE>Accessibility is mandatory for public and admin surfaces.</RULE>
    <RULE>Responsive behavior is required on mobile and desktop.</RULE>
    <RULE>All publish-state transitions must be testable.</RULE>
    <RULE>Auth and permission checks must have explicit coverage.</RULE>
  </QUALITY_BARS>

  <PHASED_DELIVERY_PLAN>
    <PHASE id="P1" title="Foundation and Auth Unification">
      <OBJECTIVE>Stabilize the repo before CMS expansion.</OBJECTIVE>
      <SCOPE>
        <ITEM>Choose and implement one auth/session strategy.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Create shared role/permission helpers for admin, editor, author, member, and optional listing manager.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Add initial test harness and first auth/guard tests.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Document migration away from mock-dependent session assumptions.</ITEM>
      </SCOPE>
    </PHASE>

    <PHASE id="P2" title="CMS Data Model and Admin Skeleton">
      <OBJECTIVE>Add Prisma entities and admin navigation for CMS-managed content.</OBJECTIVE>
      <SCOPE>
        <ITEM>Create CMS entities, enums, relations, and migration plan.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Add content list/detail/create/edit flows in admin.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Introduce status workflow, SEO fields, and media references.</ITEM>
      </SCOPE>
    </PHASE>

    <PHASE id="P3" title="Public Route Refactor and Content Rendering">
      <OBJECTIVE>Move public pages from mock/static composition to CMS-backed rendering.</OBJECTIVE>
      <SCOPE>
        <ITEM>Refactor landing and informational pages into route-native server-first rendering.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Back blog and longform content with CMS entities.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Back listing detail SEO content with persistent content fields and blocks.</ITEM>
      </SCOPE>
    </PHASE>

    <PHASE id="P4" title="Preview, Scheduling, and Publishing Operations">
      <OBJECTIVE>Complete true CMS workflow functionality.</OBJECTIVE>
      <SCOPE>
        <ITEM>Preview tokens and unpublished rendering.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Scheduled publishing and archived states.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Revision metadata and publish audit trail.</ITEM>
      </SCOPE>
    </PHASE>

    <PHASE id="P5" title="Operational Hardening">
      <OBJECTIVE>Raise the platform to releasable quality.</OBJECTIVE>
      <SCOPE>
        <ITEM>Testing expansion across critical paths.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>SEO validation, sitemap enrichment, metadata verification.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Accessibility pass, responsive QA, and performance cleanup.</ITEM>
        <ITEM>Developer and operator documentation.</ITEM>
      </SCOPE>
    </PHASE>
  </PHASED_DELIVERY_PLAN>

  <RISKS_AND_MITIGATIONS>
    <RISK severity="high">Dual auth causes broken role enforcement and inconsistent session semantics.</RISK>
    <MITIGATION>Resolve auth before content migration and do not add CMS permissions on top of both systems.</MITIGATION>

    <RISK severity="high">Mock data usage hides missing backend behavior and can create false completion signals.</RISK>
    <MITIGATION>Track every mock-backed surface and replace it with persistent read/write paths phase by phase.</MITIGATION>

    <RISK severity="high">Marketplace-specific schema may resist generic CMS growth if expanded ad hoc.</RISK>
    <MITIGATION>Introduce CMS entities intentionally, keep listing as a first-class content type, and avoid overloading existing tables with unrelated semantics.</MITIGATION>

    <RISK severity="medium">Large client components may make preview, SEO, and testability harder.</RISK>
    <MITIGATION>Refactor route by route toward server-first data loading and smaller interactive islands.</MITIGATION>

    <RISK severity="medium">No current automated tests increase refactor risk.</RISK>
    <MITIGATION>Establish a test baseline in the foundation phase and block major migrations without executable coverage.</MITIGATION>
  </RISKS_AND_MITIGATIONS>

  <VERIFICATION_STRATEGY>
    <CODE_QUALITY>
      <STEP>Run lint on every meaningful slice.</STEP>
      <STEP>Run build after structural or route changes.</STEP>
      <STEP>Run targeted Bun tests as coverage is added.</STEP>
    </CODE_QUALITY>
    <PRODUCT_VERIFICATION>
      <STEP>Verify role-based access for admin/editor/author/member/listing-manager paths.</STEP>
      <STEP>Verify preview and publish-state transitions.</STEP>
      <STEP>Verify multilingual route behavior and metadata.</STEP>
      <STEP>Verify listing search, detail rendering, and editorial rendering against persistent data.</STEP>
      <STEP>Verify review moderation and operational status changes still update derived public data correctly.</STEP>
    </PRODUCT_VERIFICATION>
    <RELEASE_GATES>
      <GATE>Zero mock dependency in claimed-complete CMS flows.</GATE>
      <GATE>Single auth system only.</GATE>
      <GATE>Publish workflow demonstrably functional.</GATE>
      <GATE>Critical admin and public routes pass lint, build, and targeted tests.</GATE>
    </RELEASE_GATES>
  </VERIFICATION_STRATEGY>

  <OPEN_DECISIONS>
    <DECISION id="OD-01">Should the current adult-marketplace domain remain the long-term product domain, or is the repo only a technical scaffold for a broader startup CMS?</DECISION>
    <DECISION id="OD-02">Should the OWNER role remain a first-class operator role in v1 CMS, or be deferred until editorial/admin flows are stable?</DECISION>
    <DECISION id="OD-03">Should blog, changelog, and case studies share one generic post model with typed subtypes, or separate models with shared rendering primitives?</DECISION>
  </OPEN_DECISIONS>

  <IMMEDIATE_NEXT_ACTIONS>
    <ACTION priority="1">Create an implementation plan derived from this PRD, starting with auth unification and test harness setup.</ACTION>
    <ACTION priority="2">Inventory every mock-backed UI surface and map each one to a target persistent data source.</ACTION>
    <ACTION priority="3">Design the first Prisma migration for CMS entities and publish states before editing public routes.</ACTION>
  </IMMEDIATE_NEXT_ACTIONS>
</PROJECT_PRD>
